<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Categories on Lochana Perera</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Categories on Lochana Perera</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Attention is all you need</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 16:52:57 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was high tide&amp;ndash;spring tide, if you will&amp;ndash;at half past-six o&amp;rsquo;clock
on a warm June evening: not the commonplace ebb and flow of a vulgar
river; but the mighty tide of fashion&amp;rsquo;s wonderful sea, surging
westward, under the dusty elms and lindens of the Lady&amp;rsquo;s Mile. If
you had driven round this very park between four and five on this
very afternoon, you would have been gratified by the sight of some
half-dozen nursemaids with their straggling charges, an occasional girl
and perambulator, a picturesque life guardsman here and there, making a
little spot of crimson amongst the wavering shadows of the trees, a few
hulking idlers in corduroy and bluchers, and a tipsy female sleeping
on the grass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the excited policemen have enough to do to keep the
four ranks of carriages in line, and to rescue foot-passengers from
the pawing hoofs of three-hundred-guinea steeds. The walk under the
trees is as crowded as the enclosure at Ascot, and the iron chairs are
as fully occupied as the seats in a fashionable chapel. The pouncing
proprietor, with the leathern pouch at his side, has hard work to
collect his rents, so rapidly do his customers come and go, and is
distracted by vague fears of levanting tenants and bad debts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On all the length of the rails between Hyde-Park Corner and the Serpentine
there is scarcely room for one lounger more, for the rule of fashion
is so subtile a bondage, that it has compelled millions of people who
never in all their lives have spoken to one another to wear the same
order of garments, and talk the same slang, and ride in the same kind
of carriages, and eat the same class of dinners, and congregate in
the same places, at the same hour, year after year, and century after
century, from the earliest dawn of civilisation until to-day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 16:52:57 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, robotics has been catching up with the LLM era. Pi’s π0.5 can clean unseen homes. Tesla’s Optimus can follow natural language cooking instructions. These systems are extremely impressive, but they feel stuck in a utilitarian mindset of robotic appliances. For these future robots to live with us, they must be expressive. Expressiveness communicates internal state such as intent, attention, and confidence. Beyond its functional utility as a communication channel, expressiveness makes interactions feel natural. Without it, you get the textbook uncanny valley effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I came across Apple’s ELEGNT paper, which frames this idea rigorously through a Pixar-like lamp to show how posture and timing alone can convey intention. Around the same time, I discovered SpiRobs, a soft tentacle robot that feels oddly alive with just simple movements. One system was carefully designed to express intent while the other just moved, yet somehow felt like it had intent. That difference was interesting. I started building Shoggoth Mini as a way to explore it more directly. Not with a clear goal, but to see what would happen if I pushed embodiment into stranger territory. This post retraces that process, the happy accidents, and what I learned about building robots.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
