<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Lochana Perera</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Lochana Perera</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 16:52:57 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Attention is all you need</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 16:52:57 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was high tide&amp;ndash;spring tide, if you will&amp;ndash;at half past-six o&amp;rsquo;clock
on a warm June evening: not the commonplace ebb and flow of a vulgar
river; but the mighty tide of fashion&amp;rsquo;s wonderful sea, surging
westward, under the dusty elms and lindens of the Lady&amp;rsquo;s Mile. If
you had driven round this very park between four and five on this
very afternoon, you would have been gratified by the sight of some
half-dozen nursemaids with their straggling charges, an occasional girl
and perambulator, a picturesque life guardsman here and there, making a
little spot of crimson amongst the wavering shadows of the trees, a few
hulking idlers in corduroy and bluchers, and a tipsy female sleeping
on the grass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the excited policemen have enough to do to keep the
four ranks of carriages in line, and to rescue foot-passengers from
the pawing hoofs of three-hundred-guinea steeds. The walk under the
trees is as crowded as the enclosure at Ascot, and the iron chairs are
as fully occupied as the seats in a fashionable chapel. The pouncing
proprietor, with the leathern pouch at his side, has hard work to
collect his rents, so rapidly do his customers come and go, and is
distracted by vague fears of levanting tenants and bad debts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On all the length of the rails between Hyde-Park Corner and the Serpentine
there is scarcely room for one lounger more, for the rule of fashion
is so subtile a bondage, that it has compelled millions of people who
never in all their lives have spoken to one another to wear the same
order of garments, and talk the same slang, and ride in the same kind
of carriages, and eat the same class of dinners, and congregate in
the same places, at the same hour, year after year, and century after
century, from the earliest dawn of civilisation until to-day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 16:52:57 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;this is the test post&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
